Dublin, Ireland (a) +353 89 23 85 783 > +385 97 77 66 221⊠ aleksandar.topuzovic@gmail.com in aleksandar.topuzovic atopuzov

Aleksandar Topuzović

Professional Profile

A highly skilled and experienced senior software engineer with in-depth and extensive knowledge of software development, operating systems, networking and distributed systems. Has a strong understanding of a wide range of software, hardware and networking concepts. Is able to quickly diagnose sources of reliability and performance bottlenecks, propose and implement solutions for correcting them. Highly organized and methodological, with exceptional attention to detail and an eye for correctness and accuracy. Dedicated to providing only the highest standards of service. Readily improves his skill set and knowledge. Welcomes challenges, learns fast and adapts well to new situations and opportunities. Have worked in multiple engineering teams to develop complex tools and solutions for international clients. Has a keen interest in functional programming and distributed systems.

Education

2011 Master of Engineering in Computer Science, University of Zagreb, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Croatia.

Thesis: Determining technical trading rules using genetic programming

https://github.com/atopuzov/gp-market-trading

https://www.bib.irb.hr/526695/download/526695.diplomski.pdf

Work Experience

Sep 2015 to Software Engineer, Demonware (Activision-Blizzard), Dublin, Ireland.

- Dec 2018 developed automation tooling and services
 - developed features on a custom orchestration system
 - developed and built systems to support deployment of services
 - o delivered a container orchestration platform

Nov 2012 to **Systems Engineer**, Amazon, Dublin, Ireland.

- Sep 2015 developed automation tooling and services for large scale management and monitoring of the load-balancing platform
 - developed internal libraries and tools
 - o participated in the on call rotation and assisted with troubleshooting and performance optimization
 - participated in the hiring process

2012 to Nov Software Developer, 2x2 Games, Zagreb, Croatia.

2012 o ported game (Unity of Command) to the Mac OS X platform

- developed the necessary tooling for releasing the game on multiple platforms
- o developed game features

2005 to Nov Freelance, Zagreb, Croatia.

2012 • installed and administered linux servers

- o designed, implemented and administered networking infrastructure
- o developed tooling for large scale linux and network management and monitoring
- o helped with troubleshooting, optimizing and securing services and infrastructure
- developed web applications
- o provided training on linux systems and networking

July 2006 to Networking Group Team Leader, Croatian Motorways, Zagreb, Croatia.

2010 • participated in public procurement

- o planed and oversaw the activities of the networking group
- coordinated work with customers, vendors and partners
- o managed a team of engineers

April 2005 to Senior Network Engineer, Croatian Motorways, Zagreb, Croatia.

July 2006 • installed and administered linux, solaris and windows servers

- designed and administered a country wide network
- o developed network automation and monitoring tooling
- optimized the networking infrastructure

October 2003 Systems Engineer, Croatian Motorways, Zagreb, Croatia.

to April 2005 o installed and administered linux and solaris servers

• developed automation tooling

2001 to 2003 Systems, Network and Build Engineer, AVL, Zagreb, Croatia.

- \circ installed and administered *nix servers, linux workstations and network infrastructure
- \circ managed build system for linux and irix

2000 to 2001 Systems and Network Engineer, Ruđer Bošković Institute, Zagreb, Croatia.

- o administered linux servers and network infrastructure
- developed automation tooling

Professional Development

2018 Erlang training, Erlang Solutions, Dublin, Ireland.

2012-2018 Conferences attended.

- FOSDEM
- Kubecon
- o Euro Python, PyCon IE
- o Lambda Days, Lambda World
- o Monadic Party Haskell Summer School

continuous Online MOOCs by Coursera, EdX, Udacity etc..

- o On programming languages, Scala, Haskell, Erlang, Ocaml, Standard ML, Racket
- $\circ\,$ Algorithms, Networking, Cryptography, Machine Learning, AI, Compilers
- 2007 Project Management, Faculty of Civil Engineering, University of Zagreb, Croatia.

2003 to 2007 CISCO network training, Croatia.

- o CCNA, CCNP, CCVP, MPLS, Security and VPN
- $\circ~$ Workshop on optical technologies

Languages

Croatian Native speaker

English Fluent Business English Certificate Higher Grade A, IELTS Academic Band 8

German Intermediate

Spanish Basic

Skills

Development Python, Haskell, Bash, C, Git, sql

Ops Linux, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, Prometheus